# **Srinivas Patha**

Senior Software Consultant

## Profile

A competent professional with 10+ years of experience in full-stack development on Microsoft Technologies in Software Development and skilled in C#.Net, Asp.Net Core, Asp.Net MVC, SQL Server, Web API, Angular, React, Vue JS, WCF, Backbone JS, jQuery, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Power BI along Azure, AWS.

# Employment History

## Senior Consultant .NET at SoftwareONE

February 2022 — Present

- Design and development of User Interfaces using ASP.NET Core, C#, Restful, XML & HTML, React. for Various Applications based on the scope of the applications and provide solutions for insurance systems that can interface with third-party software and operating environments using .Net.
- Created CI/CD pipelines using Git Actions / AWS CodeBuild, and Deploy.
- Software Engineer skilled with SDLC methodologies such as Waterfall, Iterative, and Agile model projects experience and proficiency in object-oriented programming, design, and development.
- Interacted with end-users and business analysts to identify business requirements and gather requirements for business logic fulfillment, Analysis, and coding of applications.
- Worked as a technical lead in the team for the design and development of applications using Microsoft Visual Studio with modernizing .Net Applications from MVC to REST-oriented architecture.
- Responsible for reviewing merge requests for all team members and merging them into the master branch in Git Lab.

#### **Senior Consultant**

December 2021 — February 2022

- Created a web application using Blazor technology with .Net core framework 5.0 to scheduler application for monitor the Jobs which Admin can run as Adhoc.
- Implemented JWT Token Authentication for API based Application.
- Implemented WEB API Services for CRUD operations with HTTP verbs GET, POST, PUT and DELETE.
- Implemented in configuring Swagger UI, Postman to the WEB API Core.
- Developed Unit-test with Xunit Library for Shared Modules.
- Implemented third party providers with WEB API to download the files.

#### **Details**

+14696348983 srinivaspatha@gmail.com

#### Skills

C#, .Net Core, Blazor

ASP.NET, ASP.NET Core, MVC

JavaScript, Jquery, Vue Js, Angular, React JS

Web API, SQL

Power BI,SSIS,SSRS

Microsoft Azure, AWS

Agile and Scrum, Jira

Communication Skills

Leadership and Teamwork

Fast Learner

#### Links

https://www.linkedin.in/srinivaspatha

#### **Senior Consultant**

July 2021 — November 2021

- Scope of the application is to manage employee leave, rosters, expense using ASP.NET MVC Core with Angular, Azure Storage, Azure Functions, Azure Web APP, SQL Server.
- Developed the Azure CI/CD with Devops for deployment process.
- Major module users are corporate HR, Admin and facilities team, corporate finance.
- These users will pull data from these module and handle employee payroll, attendance, claim management and reimbursements.
- Implemented XUnit test cases to get the coverage metrics and bugs and vulnerability of application with sonarqube integration.

#### Lead Software Engineer at SS&C Technologies

June 2012 — May 2021

## **Lead Software Enginner**

August 2018 — July 2021

- Developed Application on using Visual Studio 2019, C#, React, Redux, HTML, CSS, AJAX, IIS, C#, ASP.NET, JavaScript, XML and High Charts and closely following MVC Architecture
- Implemented independent of shared models and database layers.
- Developed ASP.NET Web API services to return Json format.
- Create and modified SQL database tables, store procedures, triggers and functions.
- Integrated High Charts to show the visualizations in different format Bar, Pie, Heat Map, Area, drill down and tabular Charts.
- Developed Individual console projects to run as services to run the background process.
- Developed NUnit Test cases to coverage the code and integrated with sonarqube.

#### **Senior Software Engineer**

June 2016 — July 2018

- Developed Application on using Visual Studio 2013/2019, C#, Angular 4/6, ASP.Net MVC, HTML5 and CSS and closely following MVC Architecture
- Implemented independent of shared models and database layers.
- Developed ASP.NET Web API services to return Json format and consuming third-party Web Services and REST, WPF, WCF Services.
- Extensive experience working with data providers and datasets connecting to an SQL database.
- Create and modified SQL database tables, create or modify table constraints and create indexes, store procedures, triggers and functions.
- Created SSIS package to import data from various file formats and applied transformations to Implement enhancements for better performance.
- Developed DAL, Data Modeling using ADO.NET, LINQ and Unit Test scripts.

 rewritten/refactored the code improve the performance and maintained easily.

## **Senior Software Engineer**

September 2015 — May 2016

- Designed and developed .NET applications using C#.NET and ASP.NET.
- Developed Telerik controls for Customized grid and auto load drop down controls, Business and Data Access layers using C#, Web Services and ADO.NET.
- Development of the application using n-tier distributed architecture.
- Used ADO.NET for data access layer to communicate with the SQL Server database.
- Worked on Windows Presentation Foundation. Implemented changes to as per the requirements.
- Involved in Software Development Life Cycle starting from requirements gathering and performed object-oriented analysis and design using UML.
- Involved in the development of SOAP based XML Web Services like Financial account management.
- Involved in NUnit testing of the application.
- Involved in deployment and post production support for the application.

## **Software Engineer**

March 2013 — August 2015

- Involved in Enhancing the Business Layer to provide more interfaces and functions needed for the system for reusable.
- Converted the JCL Templates to equivalent to C# code. By selecting the dynamic generating tags so that User Can update the data based on Tags.
- Used N-tier architecture for presentation, Business, and Data Access Layers.
- Developed Business Logic with C#, Good knowledge of relational database in oracle.
- Developed Web forms using ASP.Net server controls and validated input using JavaScript.
- Responsible for the fixing the bugs, testing and troubleshooting the technical problems.
- Worked with ADO.NET with web services for CURD Operation using SQL.
- Created different tables, views, and indexes and normalized the
- Worked on the agile methodologies throughout the project life cycle.
- Used ADO.NET objects such as Data Adapter, Data Reader, and Data Set for consistent access to the data store.
- Wrote Triggers, which send e-mails to the client after successful transactions.

- Writing Database routines, stored procedures, and fixing up standard specifications.
- Used Data Transformation Services to import the data in SQL server from heterogeneous data sources like Oracle.

### **Software Engineer**

June 2012 — February 2013

- Designed and developed front-end applications using ASPX and Telerik Library for tables and Asynchronous Integration for Grid and Loading data.
- Developed Application on using Visual Studio 2009, C#, ASP.Net, ADO.NET, HTML and CSS with Object Oriented Programming Techniques and closely following MVC Architecture
- Implemented the Middle tier and Business logic using C#.
- Developed WCF services to return XML Format.
- Extensive experience working with data providers and datasets connecting to an SQL database.
- Create and modified SQL database tables, create or modify table constraints and create indexes.
- Wrote store procedures, triggers and functions as per the requirements.

## Software Engineer at Analogics India Pvt Ltd

February 2012 — June 2012

- As a Junior Engineer responsible for fixing bugs, testing, and troubleshooting technical problems.
- Developed Application on using Visual Studio 2009, C#, ASP.Net, ADO.NET, HTML and CSS with Object Oriented Programming Techniques.
- Implemented the Middle tier and Business logic using C#.
- Involved in Unit Testing of the implemented modules.

## Education

Bachelor of Technology in Computer Science and Engineering, Jawaharlal Nehru Technology University

August 2005 — August 2009